Desmond O'Grady papers, 1953-2001
Emory University
- Printed material, 1953-2001, Series 5; Boxes 64 - 77, OP 2-12
  The Desmond O'Grady papers include many collected publications--clippings and entire magazines and journals--with material by or about O'Grady. These printed materials have been arranged into three Subseries. Subseries 5.1 contains Writings by O'Grady and is divided under the headings, Publications with poems and Publications with prose and interviews. O'Grady's printed works are arranged alphabetically by title. Writings about O'Grady (Subseries 5.2) contains Reviews and Profiles and promotional items arranged alphabetically by title. Subseries 5.3, Other printed material, includes Individual printed works by others (alphabetical by author when known, by title when author is unidentified), Magazines and Pamphlets (alphabetical by title), Art exhibit pamphlets (alphabetical by artist when known, by title when artist is unknown or multiple artists contributed to exhibit), Miscellaneous/Newspaper clippings (alphabetical by subject), and Promotional items.
  Organized into three subseries: (5.1) Writings by O'Grady, (5.2) Writings about O'Grady, and (5.3) Other printed material.
  - Writings by Desmond O'Grady, 1964-2000, Subseries 5.1; Boxes 64 - 67: folder 20
    - Publications with poems
    - "Agave" (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - "Annual Holiday," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - "August Weekend," in The Irish Times, 29 August, 1998 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - "Autumn Festival," in The Poet's Voice, Autumn 1999 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - "Berlin Metro" (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - "Bettina's Song" (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - "Bois de Boulogne," translation, in Tracks, 1986 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - "Canto of the Last Witness," in The Irish Press, 14 February, 1970 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - "Cavafy in Alexandria," in Ploughshares, Vol. 6, No. 1 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - "Celtic Sura" (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Chords and Orchestrations, partial copy with annotations8 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - The Dark Edge of Europe, Title page (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - "Days," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979 [See Subseries 5.1, "Annual Holiday," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979] (Box -, -)
    - "Day Trip" (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - "Dream," in Southword, Summer 2000 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - "A Drowned Fisherman Aged 21" (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - The Dying Gaul (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - "Epithalamium" (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - "Ezra Pound in Venice," in Krino, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - "Farewell" (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - "Farewell," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983 (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - "Fathers and Sons," in Limerick Socialist, May 1977 (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - "Female Visitation" (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - "Flute Player," in Horizons, Summer, 1978 (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - "Flute Player" (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - "Fo Fo," in Ploughshares, Vol. 6, No. 1 [See Subseries 5.1, "Cavafy in Alexandria," in Ploughshares, Vol. 6, No. 1] (Box -, -)
    - "Girl" (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - "Grandfather" (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - "Grandson," in Chapman, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - "Grandson," in Force 10, Issue 10 (Box 64, Folder 29)
    - "Grandson," in The Poet's Voice, Autumn 1999 [See Subseries 5.1, "Autumn Festival," in The Poet's Voice, Autumn 1999] (Box -, -)
    - "Graveyard" (Box 64, Folder 30)
    - "The Great Horse Fair" (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - "Halloween," in Chapman [See Subseries 5.1, "Grandson," in Chapman] (Box -, -)
    - "Halloween," in The Poet's Voice, Autumn 1999 [See Subseries 5.1, "Autumn Festival" in The Poet's Voice, Autumn 1999] (Box -, -)
    - "Harper," in Horizons, Summer, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Flute Player," in Horizons, Summer, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - The Head-Gear of the Tribe (Box 64, Folder 32)
    - Hellas (Box 64, Folder 33)
    - "Herons," in L imerick Socialist, December 1979 [See Subseries 5.1, "Annual Holiday," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979] (Box -, -)
    - "His Ghost to Hamlet," in Poetry Ireland Review, Winter 1988 (Box 64, Folder 34)
    - "His Ghost to Hamlet" (Box 64, Folder 35)
    - "History" (Box 64, Folder 36)
    - "Home Haven" (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - "Homecoming," in The Atlantic Monthly, January, 1964 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - "Hospitality" (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - "House" (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - "I am Ireland" (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - "Ignorant of the World," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1977-1978 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - "Impromptu" (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - "In Exile," translation, in Tracks, 1986 [See Subseries 5.1 "Bois de Boulogne," translation, in Tracks, 1986] (Box -, -)
    - "In Memoriam John Tamburro" (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - "In My Generation," in Limerick Socialist, May 1977 [See Subseries 5.1, "Fathers and Sons," in Limerick Socialist, May 1977] (Box -, -)
    - "Inheritance" (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - "Initiates" (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - "The Irish Anthology Sura," in Limerick Socialist (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - "The Irish College at Louvain" (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - "An Irish Exile in Liege" (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - "Island," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983 [See Subseries 5.1, "Farewell," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983] (Box -, -)
    - "John Berryman," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "John Berryman" (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - "Joseph Brodsky Visits," in Southword, Summer 2000 [See Subseries 5.1, "Dream," in Southword, Summer 2000] (Box -, -)
    - "Kinsale" (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - "Landfall" (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - "Landlord," in The Irish Press, 29 December, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - "Limerick: Ireland," in The Lace Curtain, Summer 1970 (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - "Marcus' Birthday" (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - "The Mental Traveller" (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - "Midwinter," in Cyphers, Winter/Spring 1983 (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - "Midwinter" (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - "Mise Raifteri," in The Irish Press, 19 August, 1970 (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - "Mistress Mine," in Open Places, Fall 1981 (Box 65, Folder 24)
    - "Morning," in Cyphers, Winter/Spring 1983 [See Subseries 5.1, "Midwinter," in Cyphers, Winter/Spring 1983] (Box -, -)
    - "Morning" (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - "Mountain" (Box 65, Folder 26)
    - "Mustanbih," translation, in Poetry, October-November 1995 (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - "My Country" (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - "My Day for Pastroudis," in The Stony Thursday Book, No. 7 (Box 65, Folder 29)
    - "My Son's Birthday" (Box 65, Folder 30)
    - "The Nail," in Rome Daily American, 22 November, 1965 (Box 65, Folder 31)
    - "Nausicaa," in Outposts, Spring 1995 (Box 65, Folder 32)
    - "Odyssey," in Chapman [See Subseries 5.1, "Grandson," in Chapman] (Box -, -)
    - "The Old Head" (Box 65, Folder 33)
    - "The Old Head Said to Me...," in Old Headlines (Box 65, Folder 34)
    - "The Old Men" (Box 65, Folder 35)
    - "On Board Ship," in Volume (Box 65, Folder 36)
    - "Origins," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983 [See Subseries 5.1, "Farewell," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983] (Box -, -)
    - "Our Lady of Savignano," in Rimbus, Summer 1980 (Box 65, Folder 37)
    - "Ovid from Exile," in Poetry Ireland Review, Autumn 1989 (Box 65, Folder 38)
    - "Ovid from Exile" (Box 65, Folder 39)
    - "Paraphernalia" (Box 65, Folder 40)
    - "Pieta One," in The Lace Curtain, Summer 1970 [See Subseries 5.1, "Limerick: Ireland," in The Lace Curtain, Summer 1970] (Box -, -)
    - "Pieta Two," in The Lace Curtain, Summer 1970 [See Subseries 5.1, "Limerick: Ireland," in The Lace Curtain, Summer 1970] (Box -, -)
    - "The Poet and His Dog" (Box 65, Folder 41)
    - "The Poet and His Dog," in Limerick Socialist [See Subseries 5.1, "The Irish Anthology Sura"] (Box -, -)
    - "The Poet and His Dog," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "The Poet in Old Age Fishing at Evening," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983 [See Subseries 5.1, "Farewell," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983] (Box -, -)
    - "The Poet in Old Age Fishing at Evening," in The Kilkenny Magazine, Autumn-Winter, 1961 (Box 65, Folder 42)
    - "The Poet's Request," in Limerick Socialist [See Subseries 5.1, "The Irish Anthology Sura] (Box -, -)
    - Poetry of Eugenio Montale, translated by O'Grady, in Arena, Spring 1965 (Box 65, Folder 43)
    - "Requiem for Paddy O'Reilley," in The Boston Irish News, February, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 44)
    - "Requiem for Paddy O'Reilley," in Limerick Socialist, May 1977 [See Subseries 5.1, "Fathers and Sons," in Limerick Socialist, May 1977] (Box -, -)
    - "The Ruin" (Box 65, Folder 45)
    - The Scattering (Box 65, Folder 46)
    - "The Scattering," in Rome Daily American, 22 November, 1965 [See Subseries 5.1, "The Nail," in Rome Daily American, 22 November, 1965] (Box -, -)
    - "Seabird" (Box 65, Folder 47)
    - Separations, Title page (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Sing Me Creation (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - "Spring," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979 [See Subseries 5.1, "Annual Holiday," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979] (Box -, -)
    - "Spring" (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - "Spring in Salzburg," in The Poet's Voice, December 1995 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - "St. John's Day, Midsummer," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979 [See Subseries 5.1, "Annual Holiday," in Limerick Socialist, December 1979] (Box -, -)
    - "St. John's Day, Midsummer," in Nimbus Two, Spring 1981 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - "Sunrise" (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - "Suras of the Wandering Celt," in Limerick Socialist, June, 1978 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - "Suras of the Wandering Celt," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "This City," in The Stony Thursday Book, No. 7 [See Subseries 5.1, "My Day for Pastroudis," in The Stony Thursday Book, No. 7] (Box -, -)
    - "Three Photographs" (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - "Tipperary" [See Subseries 5.1, "Berlin Metro"] (Box -, -)
    - "Tipperary," in Poetry Ireland Review, Spring 1988 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Tipperary, Book Jacket (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - "To John Montague at 60," in The Canadian Journal of Irish Studies, July 1989 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - "Two Sonnets from La Vita Nuova" (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - "Umm Kalthoum" (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - "Unfinished Pieta," in The Lace Curtain, Summer 1970 [See Subseries 5.1, "Limerick: Ireland," in The Lace Curtain, Summer 1970] (Box -, -)
    - "Versions from Greek," in Agenda, 1979/80 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - "Vista dal Campidoglio" (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - "Vocation," in The Living Stream: A Festschrift for Theo Dorgan (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - "Vocation," in The Poet's Voice, Autumn 1999 [See Subseries 5.1, "Autumn Festival," in The Poet's Voice, Autumn 1999] (Box -, -)
    - "The Voyage" [See Subseries 5.1, "The Mental Traveller"] (Box -, -)
    - "The Wandering King: The Golden Ode of Imr Al-Qais," translation, in Agenda, Spring 1983 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - "A Weakness for Women," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1977-1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Ignorant of the World," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1977-1978] (Box -, -)
    - "The Wide World," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983 [See Subseries 5.1, "Farewell," in English Literature Society, 27 January, 1983] (Box -, -)
    - "The Wide World" (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - "A Willow Sprig" (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - "A Willow Sprig," in The Canadian Journal of Irish Studies, July 1989 [See also Subseries 5.1, "To John Montague at 60," in The Canadian Journal of Irish Studies, July 1989 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - "Winter," in Cyphers, Winter/Spring 1988-1989 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - "With Johannes Edfelt in Sweden," in Artes, June 1987 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - "Woman" [See Subseries 5.1, "Seabird"] (Box -, -)
    - "Work Break" (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - "Work in Progress," in Two Rivers, Winter 1969 (Box 66, Folder 24)
    - "The World's Lovemonger" (Box 66, Folder 25)
    - "Writing Out of Doors," in Limerick Socialist [See Subseries 5.1, "The Irish Anthology Sura"] (Box -, -)
    - Publications with prose and interviews
    - "Arab Poetry: A Continuum" (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - "As Modern Dublin Grows, City of Joyce's 'Ulysses' is Steadily Vanishing," in Daily American, 28 October, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - "Beckett in Paris," in Journal of Beckett Studies, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - "Being Irish Is Not Enough," in Evening Press, 11 October, 1962 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - "Big Circle Covers Rome's History" (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - "The Burden of the Past and Modern Irish Poetry," in Harvard Celtic Colloquium, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - "The Burden of the Past and the Creative Imagination" (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - "Cavafy and Cubism," in Third Kavafis International Symposium, 1993 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - "Desmond O'Grady's Rome," in Hibernia, February, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - "Escape to East or West," in Limerick Tribune, 18 November, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - "Ezra Pound: A Personal Memoir," in Agenda, Ezra Pound Special Issue, 1979-80 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - "Ezra Pound and Creative Translation," in Ezra Pound a Venezia, 1985 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - "Ezra Pound and Creative Translation," in Irish Translators' Association Newsletter, June 1989 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - "First Committee Report," in Actes Du XIe Congres De L.O.M.P., 1995 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - "From Limerick to the Left Bank," in The Old Limerick Journal, French Edition (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - "A General Introduction to My Work," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "A Grecian Glance" (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - "Inheritance," in Butcher's Journal, May 1979 (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - "Inheritance," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "Italy Hopes for a Record Season," in Irish Independent, 11 July, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - "Nadine Gordimer Speaks Out," in Book World, 15 July, 1984 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - "A Night With Osers," in The Poet's Voice, December 1995 [See Subseries 5.1, "Spring in Salzburg," in The Poet's Voice, December 1995] (Box -, -)
    - "Patrick Kavanagh in Rome, 1965: A Personal Memoir," in The Poetry Ireland Review, Spring/Summer, 1992 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Writings about Desmond O'Grady, 1965-2001, Subseries 5.2; Boxes 67: folder 21 - 68
    - Reviews
    - "Desmond O'Grady's, Translations," by Alan Neame, in Agenda, March 1995 [review of Trawling Tradition] (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - "A Full Catch," by Michael Smith, in The Irish Times, 19 April, 1997 [review of The Road Taken and Trawling Tradition] (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - "Ireland-The Grit and the Substance," by Patrick Gallagher [review of The Seven Arab Odes] (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - "Longing for the Ultimate Thereness," by Desmond Fennell, in Irish Literary Supplement, Autumn 1992 [review of Tipperary] (Box 67, Folder 24)
    - "New Poetry," by Michael Hartnett, in The Irish Times, 17 March, 1978 [review of Sing Me Creation] (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - "Passionate and to the Point," by Fred Johnston, in The Irish Times, 1 May, 1999 [review of O'Grady's translation of C.P. Cavafy's Selected Poems] (Box 67, Folder 26)
    - "Poems are Found in Translation," by Donall O'Shea, in Weekend Cork Examiner, 30 July, 1994 [review of Trawling Tradition] (Box 67, Folder 27)
    - "Poetry in the Clouds," by Patrick Crotty, in Irish Times, 11 April, 1992 [review of Tipperary] (Box 67, Folder 28)
    - Review of The Dark Edge of Europe, by Thomas Kilroy, in Studies, Winter 1967 (Box 67, Folder 29)
    - Review of The Gododdin, December 1978 (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Review of The Seven Arab Odes, by Roland John in Outposts (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - Review of The Seven Arab Odes, by Fred Johnston, in The Irish Times, Summer, 1991 (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Review of Trawling Tradition, by Sean Mac Reamoinn, in Poetry Ireland Review, Spring 1995 (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - "Suspended in Letters of Gold," by Fred Johnston, in The Irish Times, 16 November, 1991 [review of The Seven Arab Odes] (Box 67, Folder 34)
    - "The Trawling Translator," by Hans-Christian oser, in Translation Ireland, June 1994 [review of Trawling Tradition] (Box 67, Folder 35)
    - "Unpaid Duties," by Conor Kelly, in Krino, July 1992 [review of Tipperary] (Box 67, Folder 36)
    - "Voyage Into the Interior," by Brenden Kennelly, in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978]
    - "Voyage Into the Interior," by Brenden Kennelly [review of Sing Me Creation] (Box 67, Folder 37)
    - "The Wild Life," by Michael Hulse, in P.N. Review [review of The Seven Arab Odes] (Box 67, Folder 38)
    - "Words of War," by Josephine Balmer, in The Independent, 18 December, 1994 [review of Trawling Tradition] (Box 67, Folder 39)
    - Profiles and promotional items
    - Newspaper clippings: news, profiles and general reviews of O'Grady, 1965-1994 (Box 67, Folder 40)
    - "At Home with a Wandering Celt," by Adam Wyeth, in Irish Examiner, 5 May 2001 (Box 67, Folder 41)
    - "Bookview-Paris," by Fred Johnston, in Galway Advertiser, 5 August 1999 (Box 67, Folder 42)
    - Brief Biography in Contemporary Authors (Box 67, Folder 43)
    - Brief Biography in Who's Who, What's What, Where's Where in Ireland, 1973 (Box 67, Folder 44)
    - Brief Biography by Brid Frawley (Box 67, Folder 45)
    - "Council Names Aosdana Members," 22 December, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 46)
    - "Desmond O'Grady, A Distinguished Son of Limerick," in Limerick Chronicle, 5 June 1971 (Box 67, Folder 47)
    - "Desmond O'Grady: A Living Gaul in Rome," by John M. Thavis, in Daily American (Box 67, Folder 48)
    - "Desmond O'Grady and Ezra Pound," by Salvatore Galioto, in Feelings (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - "Desmond O'Grady, the Wanderer from Munster," by Paul Durcan, in The Cork Examiner, 24 April, 1978 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - "Desmond O'Grady Talking to John Liddy," by John Liddy, in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "Desmond O'Grady Will Give Poetry Readings in Israel," in Limerick Chronicle, 1 January, 1972 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - "The Dying Gaul," by Gaby Ford, in Metropolitan, 16-29 September, 1996 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - "Encounter With the Poet," by John Corr, in The Philadelphia Traveler, 7 October, 1990 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - "Filiocht le Ceol Duchais," by Seamus O'Cinneide, in The Limerick Chronicle (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - "Hallucinating with Mr. Joyce," by Stan Gebler Davis, 23 June, 1990 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - "Il Vino Il Sangue," by Paolo Lagazzi, in Gazzetta de Parma, 12 April, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - "Instead of an Essay," by Eamon Grennan, in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "Instead of an Essay," by Eamon Grennan (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - "Irish Poet Returns to A.U.C.," by Ramsey Amine (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - "Kinsale Arts Launch," in The Cork Examiner, 14 June, 1989 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - "Le Strofe Rifiorite," by Emile Zucchi, in Gazzetta de Parma, 10 April, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - "Limerick Poet in Italy" (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - "Moto Perpetuo/Desmond O'Grady a Pescocostanza," 25 July, 1996 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - "A Note on the Translations of Desmond O'Grady," by Martyn Burke, in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "O'Grady: I Versi e la Memoria," by Francesca Dallatana, 13 April 1997 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - The Outsiders: Poets of Contemporary Ireland, by Frank Kersnowski, 1975 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - "The Poet as Totem," by Kevin O'Connor, in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978 [See Subseries 5.1, "Childplay," in The Stony Thursday Book, 1978] (Box -, -)
    - "Poet Desmond O'Grady Sings Out," by Hayley Silleck in Rome Daily American, 22 November, 1965 [See Subseries 5.1, "The Nail," in Rome Daily American, 22 November, 1965] (Box -, -)
    - "A Poetic Interlude in Kinsale," by John Corr (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - "Poetry Verzamelplaats van Lezer en Dichter," by William Kuipers in Volkscrant (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - "Poetry Week at the Festival of Two worlds," by Salvatore Quasimodo (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - "Savouring the Poetic Spirit," by Robert O'Byrne, in The Irish Times, 27 November, 1991 (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - "A Side Trip to a Pub Takes a Lyrical Turn," by John Corr, in The Seattle Times, 21 October, 1990 (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - "Sughero d' Oro: Oggi a Serrapetrona si Assegna il Premio," in Corriere Adriatico, 7 June, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - "A Tribute to Desmond O'Grady," by Paul Durcan, in The Cork Examiner, 5 February 1979 (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - Promotional material (Box 68, Folder 24)
    - Promotional material (Box 68, Folder 25)
    - Poster for book launch of C.P. Cavafy: Selected Poems, translated by O'Grady (Box OP2)
    - Poster for Kinsale Arts Week Festival (Box OP3)
    - Poster for La Poesia di Vincenzo Cardarelli Festival (Box OP4)
  - Other printed material, 1953-2000, Subseries 5.3; Boxes 69 - 77
    - Individual printed works
    - Benjamin, Walter, "The Storyteller" (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Cayley, John, Ink Bamboo, Book jacket (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Cummins, Walter, Shifting Borders (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - DeWolf, Samuel, With My Pen (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - du Maurier, Daphne, Don't Look Now (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Duhig, Ian, "Archbishop Mar Jacobus Remembers the Baron" (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Galioto, Salvatore, Let Us Be Modern (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Heath-Stubbs, John, "Wishes for the Month" (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Hughes, Ted, "Platform One," in The Sunday Times, 10 November, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Ivask, Astrid, "Hommage a Ivar Ivask" (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Kavanagh, Peter, Sacred Keeper: A Biography of Patrick Kavanagh (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Liddy, John, Song of the Empty Cage (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Lowry, Malcolm, Hear Us O Lord from Heaven Thy Dwelling Place (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Lubsen, Stella M., "A Chalcolithic Cypriote Anthropomorphic Figurine in the Zintilis Collection in Amsterdam" (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - MacManus, Francis, "Clan Thomas" (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Madsen, Viggo, Op. 5: "Glemslens Flod" The Rivser of Oblivion (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Odegard, Knut, Poems (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - O'Driscoll, Robert, "Greek Coda" (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Orage, A.R., "On Love" (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Piggot, Stuart, "The Problems and the Sources" (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - Potash, Larry, "Alice in Wonderland [not to be confused with America]" (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Reilly, Colin Justin Leo, The Poet Beggar's Sermon (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Russell, Peter, Le Poesie Di Manuela (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Russell, Peter, Poesie Dal Valdarno (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - Russell, Peter, Ten Days at Neumarkt (Box 69, Folder 25)
    - Rust, Rebecca, I Remember Morehead (Box 69, Folder 26)
    - Shrine, Marian, "Evening Prayer to Mary" (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - Shevoroshkin, Vitaly, "The Mother Tongue," in The Sciences, May/June 1990 (Box 69, Folder 28)
    - Vesce, Thomas E., "Feudal and Courtly Values in the Siege de Barbastre and the Buevon de Conmarchis (Box 69, Folder 29)
    - Vesce, Thomas E., "King Arthur Against Paluth" (Box 69, Folder 30)
    - Vesce, Thomas E., "Mediaeval Studies" (Box 69, Folder 31)
    - Zdanys, Jonas, "Tomas Venclova" (Box 69, Folder 32)
    - Zito, Eleanor Shiel, "Outward Bound" (Box 69, Folder 33)
    - Unidentified author